<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[The Writings of Adam M. Hopkins]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Writings of Adam M. Hopkins]]></description><link>http://amhopkins.com</link><image><url>https://amhopkins.com/images/visions-desert.jpg</url><title>The Writings of Adam M. Hopkins</title><link>http://amhopkins.com</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 06:23:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://amhopkins.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The journey to becoming a writer begins, err continues]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>In many ways, the journey began back when I was in 4th grade in Mr. Myhill&#8217;s class. He had a love for story writing, and I remember vividly sitting and writing story after story in his class. They were, of course, the sort of nonsensical stories that piqued the imagination of a 9 year old, but the settings and the characters I created are still imprinted in my memory.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Fast forward to my college years when my now wife (then girlfriend) would tease me that I was majoring in Paper Writing. Writing a 50, 60, or 100 page paper was a somewhat normal thing in college. And, without a doubt, given the opportunity, I would usually write more than what was necessary to complete the assignment.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One time in law school, a professor of mine had picked a few samples of anonymous writing that he thought was particularly well-written to share to the class. After reading my work to the class, his comment: "This is very well written, my only criticism is that it is verbose and flowery." Oof.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So it was, as I was embarking upon my legal career&#8212;&#8203;which meant that I was a professional writer&#8212;&#8203;that I sought to reign in my long-windedness and proclivity towards expressive prose.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But now, I seek to do something new.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am a writer.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And now, I am writing my first novel.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We shall see where it takes me. But, I hope to share the journey here with you.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The goal: to hold a published work of my own in my hands. Wish me luck.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://amhopkins.com/2017/10/19/The-journey-to-becoming-a-writer-begins-err-continues.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://amhopkins.com/2017/10/19/The-journey-to-becoming-a-writer-begins-err-continues.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Hopkins]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>