<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[The Writings of Adam M. Hopkins]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Writings of Adam M. Hopkins]]></description><link>http://amhopkins.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 21:21:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://amhopkins.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[I'm writing a book. What now?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am not a particularly huge fan of fiction. Or, at least not of reading fiction I should say. Sure, I have my favorite authors and books that can sweep me into that wonderful realm of being lost in a book. You know, the place that has you glued to a chair, sitting by the Lake, while the rest of your family is off to dinner. The place where you allow yourself to shirk all responsibilities in the name of finishing just one more chapter. Who doesn&#8217;t like that place?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But, to say that I am an avid reader of fiction would not be accurate. Just ask my wife. When in the bookstore, the fiction section is not usually my first stopping grounds. So, when I told my wife that I wanted to write a book, a novel to be more precise, the thought of how and why surely crossed my mind and I am sure it did my wife&#8217;s.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Nonetheless, I seek to write a novel. Surely there are more qualified writers than me. And, surely I have no clue what direction to turn when sitting down to write. Just how do you write a book?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Just sit down and write? Is that it?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But, what should I write?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>My mind was not quite this blank in reality. Having a legal background would clearly be an asset as I could simply take some old war stories and cobble them together to write a legal thriller. This was a good start, but it would not really allow me to explore some deeper meaning and issues that I wanted to express.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What are those issues you ask? I can&#8217;t tell you now. Subscribe to my mailing list, and find out more about it when the book is ready for publishing.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Suffice it to say, I was slowly slowly mulling over ideas in my head for a novel. I knew I wanted to have some legal aspect to it, and I knew that I wanted to "say" something. The book to be in my voice had to have a purpose beyond just story telling.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But the question of how still nagged me. So, enter the Internet. A little while later, I found a great resource called the "Snowflake Method" that I am going to try. Leaving aside the story that I intend to write, let&#8217;s learn about the Snowflake Method and how to apply it. So far I am only part way through the process.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I found it here: <a href="https://www.advancedfictionwriting.com/articles/snowflake-method/" class="bare">www.advancedfictionwriting.com/articles/snowflake-method/</a></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It is a ten step process:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>One sentence summary of the novel (1 hour)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>One paragraph summary of the novel (1 hour)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>One page summary for each of the main characters (1 hour per character)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Expand each sentence of the summary to a full paragraph</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>One page description of all main characters, half page for minor characters (a couple days)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Expand one page plot synopsis to 4 pages (1 week)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Expand character descriptions to character charts</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Make a list of all scenes</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Begin narrative by creating description for each scene</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Begin first draft of novel</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;ll post some more about each step in depth and how I attack it. Wish me luck.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you would like to follow my journey: <a href="https://forms.sendpulse.com/7943edcac1/">subscribe here</a>.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://amhopkins.com/2017/11/14/Im-writing-a-book-What-now.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://amhopkins.com/2017/11/14/Im-writing-a-book-What-now.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Hopkins]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The journey to becoming a writer begins, err continues]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>In many ways, the journey began back when I was in 4th grade in Mr. Myhill&#8217;s class. He had a love for story writing, and I remember vividly sitting and writing story after story in his class. They were, of course, the sort of nonsensical stories that piqued the imagination of a 9 year old, but the settings and the characters I created are still imprinted in my memory.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Mr. Myhill would bring us all down the hall into the computer lab and encourage us to write stories. Often. Whatever the idea that came to us, he wanted us to get it down on paper and explore the idea. And, to make the process all the more exciting, he began sharing parts of a story he was writing with us. We would sit huddled on the floor listening to our teacher proudly read us the stories he was himself creating.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Fast forward to my college years when my now wife (then girlfriend) would tease me that I was majoring in Paper Writing. Writing a 50, 60, or 100 page paper was a somewhat normal thing in college. And, without a doubt, given the opportunity, I would usually write more than what was necessary to complete the assignment. Expressing myself through written words has always been my preferred form of communication.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One time in law school, a professor of mine had picked a few samples of anonymous writing that he thought was particularly well-written to share to the class. Out of a rather large class, he had selected mine as an example, and read it out loud to the class. I was of course quite pleased with myself knowing the secret that it was my work. But, when he was done, his comment: "This is very well written, my only criticism is that it is verbose and flowery." Oof.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So it was. While embarking upon my legal career&#8212;&#8203;which meant that I was a professional writer&#8212;&#8203;I sought to reign in my long-windedness and proclivity towards expressive prose. I honed my writing skills to attack the point I was making. To make each word on the page meaningful in its placement and usage. My writing became tight, and for lack of a better word, lawyerly.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But now, I seek to do something new.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am a writer.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I love to write.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And now, I am writing my first novel.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>We shall see where it takes me. But, I hope to share the journey here with you.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The goal: to hold a published work of my own in my hands. Wish me luck.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you would like to follow my journey: <a href="https://forms.sendpulse.com/7943edcac1/">subscribe here</a>.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://amhopkins.com/2017/10/26/The-journey-to-becoming-a-writer-begins-err-continues.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://amhopkins.com/2017/10/26/The-journey-to-becoming-a-writer-begins-err-continues.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Hopkins]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>